

Javier Mauricio Pinilla Garcia

Date of birth: 20/03/1998 | **Nationality:** Colombian | **Gender** Male

(+57) 3054247912 | (+49) 1782337666 | <u>ing.jmpinillag@web.de</u> |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ingjavierpinilla/ https://github.com/ingjavierpinilla

Bogota, Colombia

About me: Software developer with 2 years of experience and a bachelor's degree in mechatronics engineering willing to relocate to Germany. Successfully worked on projects of deep learning, data processing, image processing, cloud services and web development in both large companies and start-ups. Experience working remotely in positions spoken entirely in English and German.

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/02/2021 - CURRENT - Bogotá, Colombia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - MAGENTRACK

Developing a web application based on microservices for monitoring patients with chronic diseases.

- Architecture design on AWS.
- Web application development.
- Integration of web application with mobile application.
- REST API creation.

Languages and technologies used: Python, Django, Pytest, MySQL, Git, Docker, AWS, Lambda, EC2, DynamoDB.

27/07/2020 - 26/10/2020 - Bogota, Colombia

DATA ANALYST - FREELANCE

Developing a web application for data visualization and manipulation.

Creating of a machine learning model to predict the total development hours of a software project in order to estimate costs at the beginning of the project.

Languages and technologies used: Python, Dash, Postgresql, Scikit-learn, AWS, S3, EC2.

13/03/2020 - 11/09/2020 - Stuttgart, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / FULL TIME INTERN - ROBERT BOSCH GMBH

- Developing a software for the reception, decoding, and storage in HDF5 format of the data coming from the sensors of autonomously driven vehicles using C++.
- Creating a software for reading and displaying the vehicle's sensors onboard the vehicle.
- Creating an application to automate ECU flashing using python (ironpython and WPF) and PRACTICE.
- Web scraping with python and beautifulsoup.

Languages and technologies used: Python, Iron Python, C++, WPF, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, HDF5, PRACTICE, SQL, Git.

26/02/2019 - 28/08/2019 - Bogota, Colombia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - BSMART EU

Developing a license plate recognition system, as well as support to different projects focused on the area of machine learning applied to images.

Languages and technologies used: Python, OpenCV, C++, MySQL.

02/02/2018 - 01/02/2019 - Bogotá, Colombia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FREELANCE

Developing an own product.

Automatic license plate recognition system developed using python together with opency where through the use of neural networks the number of colombian license plates could be obtained as a text string.

Languages and technologies used: Python, OpenCV, MySQL, AWS.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

18/01/2015 - 17/12/2020 - Bogota, Colombia

MECHATRONICS BACHELOR'S DEGREE - Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Automation Robotics. Metrology Artificial Intelligence Control engineering Sensor technology

Field(s) of study

- Information and Communication Technologies: Database and network design and administration | Interdisciplinary programmes and qualifications involving Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs) | Softwar e and applications development and analysis
- Engineering, manufacturing and construction: Electronics and automation

2.0 | 1.0 | https://unal.edu.co

30/09/2019 – 06/10/2020 – Keplerstraße 7, Stuttgart, Germany **ACADEMIC EXCHANGE YEAR** – Stuttgart Universität

I had the opportunity to attend classes related to robotics and data processing of the mechatronics master. In addition, I did an internship as a student at Robert Bosch GmbH

Field(s) of study

- Information and Communication Technologies : Database and network design and administration | Information and communication technologies not elsewhere classified | Software and applications development and analysis
- Engineering, manufacturing and construction: Electronics and automation

https://www.uni-stuttgart.de

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): SPANISH

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
GERMAN	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

python | git | GIT (GitHub) | Java Programming language | C, C++c C# | SQL/MYSQL | Machine Learning libraries Scikit-Learn Tensorflow Keras Scipy | AWS EC2 RDS S3 Lambda | Django Framework & Django REST | ReactJS | C#, WPF, WCF, SQL